Well, in this subject today,
in today's session, I'm going to tell you
something very curious that's going to shock you
quite a bit, which is the following.  Let's
go to development environments.   We're
going to go to unit two on
installing and using development environments
and we're going to install a
development environment where we're going to install Visual
Studio, to which you might say, "But
wait a second, but
last week I was saying that you won't
use Visual Studio and now in
this development environments course I'm
telling you to use
Visual Studio."
So what is the truth?  Well,
this is like the
hat game.  The programming teacher
tells you, "Don't use Visual Studio and
focus on the code," and the
development environments teacher tells you to use
Visual Studio, which is a
development environment.  Okay, Sandro, what was
Visual Studio?  Let's start there.
Okay, so what is a development environment?
Let's see.
new file 001 and from here
on development environments.
By development environment
we can understand several things.  First of
all, it is the machine, it is the computer system
in which we are going to develop
our software.
So what is meant by a
computer system?  Computer system
is the sum of
the hardware,
that is, what does your computer have?
in which you are going to develop code.   It is
understood as the
Windows, Mac or Linux operating system
and is understood as the application
with which you are going to edit code.
Regarding hardware,
obviously
the better your computer is,
the faster
you'll compile, not program, because
programming depends on you and your fingers,
right?  But the faster you compile,
the more memory you'll have for your programs and
the faster they'll run,
right?
Programming
does not require a
particularly powerful computer.
In 2025, I would say the minimum is an
octa-core processor with 8GB of
RAM
and that's it.  and a hard drive of
at least 250 GB.  Okay, those are the minimums
to be able to program from there,
and to work comfortably, let's say,
from there, the more the better.
As for the operating system, you
can
develop comfortably
on Windows, MacOS
or Linux, but you cannot develop or it is very
uncomfortable on Android or iOS.  They are
mobile operating systems designed primarily
for consuming applications, but not for
creating applications.  Are there any
exceptions?  But we are talking more about the
exception than the rule.
So, as far as the
operating system goes, use the one you like best,
okay?  And my recommendation,
obviously, over time
will be to try them all, okay?  Use
all operating systems.  And
finally, we come to the application to
make code.
What applications are there for making code?
There are countless
applications
and we are going to see what are the characteristic features
of the editors.
First, they
colorize the code
to make it
easier for you to program
and find
errors.
Two, compile the code.  They compile slash,
interpret slash, and execute the code
to, I insist, make it simpler.
Now you will see it clearly.  three eh have
aids and complements.
Four have project view, okay?
And we could say that these four characteristics
are the main ones.  But
what does this mean?  How do we
perceive these characteristics in
practice?   There
are multiple development environments
001 Visual Studio
MD installation.
The most common one today is
Visual Studio Code, whether
I like it or not, okay?  But I
actually don't like it, but okay, that's how
we're going to get into
Visual Studio Code installation first here.
First we go to the website
code.visualstudio.com.
When you enter Visual Studio you will
see a download button, right?
In my case, since I'm on Linux, it
tells me to download for Linux.
If you are on Windows, it will tell you to
download for Windows.  And those of
you on a Mac can download it on a
Mac. So I click, I download it
for, in my case, Linux, I
download it, for example, the desktop.
Okay?  And then wait for me to
understand.  I'm going to close this.  Keep.   I
'm going to close this.  I'm going to
close this.  Esto lo voy a Esto, ¿qué es?  Ah,
yes, licenses.  Close
and that's it.  Okay.
Okay.
Once we have downloaded it, once it
is downloaded, we
run the installer.
In my case, wait, there are still a
lot more windows open out there.
Okay, in my case, wait, there are thousands of
tabs open.
Let's see.  Okay, come on, here for
example.  Okay, I'm going to the desktop,
I have Visual Studio Code.  I'm going to,
in my case, open it with the
application center.
Ok, I think I already had it installed
last year.  Never mind, I'll reinstall it
.  Yes. Okay, I'll enter the password
and see what screens I find.  The
typical, I suppose, welcome screen,
of Well, you can imagine all that.
Okay, once it's installed,
once it's installed,
then we open it up
and I put Visual Studio.  You see?  I already had
one before.  I'm going to open this one
and it opens here.  And look, this is the one I
already had from last time.  This is from
some other show, right?  This is
last year.  Okay, so I'll close
here.
Let's see.  Visual Studio.  Could this be it?
I just want to try to open it.  Let it
open as much as possible, no.  Okay, so now
we're going to uninstall it to
try to make it appear the same way it
would for you.
Okay, let's see.  Un to eh un install
completely
eh Visual Studio Code for installation.
A fresh install is an
installation that's sort of like the
first time, right?  That he doesn't remember
anything.  So let's see.   Let's
go there.
Okay, okay,
okay, I'll remove the settings.
Okay, I'm
telling you that my goal is to
install it now,
okay?
Remove extensions, I think I didn't have any
extensions, but now we see them.   We
clean premises.
What I'm doing is
Linux operating system management.  It's a different story, I'll
tell you about it.  And we clean.
Okay.
Which code will tell me none.  Hosts.
Okay, well, wait
a second,
I'm going to tell you that it looks like there's something left.
Ah, snap, snap, snap, snap, snap.  Okay,
okay,
okay.  Now yes, now yes.  Okay, come on,
now I'm going to install it.  I'm
going to install it
with the goal of Hello, where are you?
with the aim of showing it to you in the
most similar way to how it comes out to
you.  Install here, password
here.
And what is Visual Studio?  Well, Visual
Studio is a development environment from
the point of view of a
code editing application.  I mean,
we've already seen that a development environment is
many things, but Visual Studio is
specifically the software editing part
, right?  This is Visual
Studio.  Very good.  Now yes,
this is the first screen we see.
Right off the bat, okay?  And we're going to see
basic use of the development environment.
Let's go to 001
usobásico.md.
Okay.  And
eh first start.
First, let's say if
we want copilot, okay?  We run
copilot assistant.
The use, the help from
artificial intelligence to program,
well, it's not part of the basic core of a
development environment, but in this case,
it is, okay?  So setup
copilot, I want to continue either with GitHub or
with Google, okay?  I log in either with
GitHub or Google, either one
.
We continue with Jithaub.
Okay, we're logged in.   Let's
open Visual Studio, okay?  And I now have
the ability to program
using artificial intelligence,
okay?  And we mark, we mark as done.
Okay.  Now, next I want to
start, I want to start working, so
for that I'm going to create a new
file.  Wait until I take this off,
okay?  And let's see, we create a new
file, in this case
Python.
Para ello, para ello
quiero un new file y se va a llamar
primera prueba.  Python new file.  I hit
enter.
Where am I going to store it?  Well, I'm
going to save it, for example, on the
desktop, okay?  I make a file
called first test.  Python.
Okay, I create a file
called first test.  Python and now next
what I'm going to do
is print
world.
Okay, so now that I've done a print hello
world,
what I want to do next
is run it.  to run it.  We'll see
that here, look, at the moment it
detects that I'm creating a
Python file, at the bottom right it
tells me, "Hey, since you're using Python, do you want
me to install Python for Visual
Studio?"  Okay, install the
Python interpreter for Visual Studio.
And I say, man, well yes, well okay,
come on.
So I get a bunch of
extensions.  Extensions
are extensions
to the functionality of the
development environment.  They are add-ons,
plugins, that is, additions, right?
Added features.
And now I continue telling me that it's done
, okay?  He tells me it's done.
I go to the first test and then
a play button will appear.  The
play button
appears play button.
The play button allows me to do so.
Click and hello world appears below, which
means that the
development environment makes it
easier for you to do
tasks such as
writing and running
code.  No, I have to open a
terminal, go to the folder, put Python
3, the file name, right?  Here I
press the play button and it automatically
compiles it and I have a terminal and it
shows me the result and everything.  Fantastic.
From the perspective of
development environments, as a development environment teacher,
I tell you it's super cool.  From a
programming point of view, no.
What I want is for you to get used to
compiling your own applications.
Okay, I'm going to make a mistake.  I'm going to
make a mistake.  I'm going to remove a
quote here, okay?  And here I'm going to say
print for a moment.
This is another line.
Okay?  If you notice,
development environments have tools that
allow us to locate errors.  If I make
a syntax error, before I
run it, it marks it in red, just like
Word, let's say.  Okay, I have
tools
for uh syntax error detection.
I'm now trying to run it and it says,
"No, no, there's an error."  Okay, but I
come here, right click, moment.
Take out, take out, take out.  Here, okay?  Fix.  Y le
puedo decir, "Arréglamelo."
And he fixes it for me.  And it's incredible.  Okay,
explain to me where I went wrong,
fix it, accept it and that's it.   It
allows you to
fix the code
even
with, well, that's it, with
artificial intelligence.
Very good.  Well, I also have the most
important thing, which is the project view.
I can open folder and in open
folder I can open DAM 2526.
Hey, do you want to save?  Yes. Okay,
so it opens up for me, well, yes, there, after
okay, it opens up for me, the same thing I have here,
really, this is very important to me
, okay?  Having the
project view on the left and being able to know
where I am at all times, okay?
So, for me, this is the most important thing
for any editor to have.  It allows you to
have a view on the left or
wherever, that's really the least of it, with
a project structure.
Very good.  From there, from
there, uh, what does Visual Studio do?  It makes our
lives easier.  As a development environment teacher, why do I have to
tell you to use Visual Studio?  Because
development environments are all about making you
work comfortably.  But as
programming teachers, I'll tell you, use Visual Studio
if you want, but don't get too used to it
, okay?  Don't let
Visual Studio do the work for
you in such a way that at some
point you don't know how to do the work
because Visual Studio is doing it,
okay?  you have to know how to do
the job.
Plus, development environments
can be customized, right?  So I
see myself, for example, here exercises 001,
new file and customization
point MD.
And from here, Visual Studio
appears in dark mode, which you guys
love because it looks very hacker-like and
very cool and very techy and all that, and
well, it's not bad.  I mean, in the
end it doesn't matter if you write
dark code or light code,
what matters is that you write code that
works, the color of the code doesn't matter.
Development environments allow for
customization, so I'm going to go to
file, I'm going to go to preferences, and within
preferences I'm going to go to, for example,
Thims, and one thing I can do is
change the theme color.  So here we go
.  Moment,
customization,
for example, changing the theme color
so you can work more comfortably.
Preferences, themes.
Color theme, well we have the
light theme.  Oh, wait now.  Okay.  Femesims,
no, wait.
Come on, go on.
Okay, we have the light theme, we have the
quiet theme,
okay?  We have the solarized theme.
Oh, sorry, not this.
[Music]
Okay, we have the theme,
the abyss,
we have the dark theme,
dark, okay?  Gris, we've got the topic,
okay?  Dark Plus,
okay, we have the monokai theme,
okay?  Okay.  Well, we
can change the color or the pattern
of the background colors.  In fact, in this
micro development environment that I'm
using, because what I'm
using in the end is still a
development environment,
but a Spartan one, okay?  But at least,
if I come here, I go to
preferences and I think that in
fonts and colors, I could
change it.  Un momento,
estaba por ahí.  Ah, here.  Okay.  Classic,
cobalt, Kate, okay?  Whatever, there are a
lot of themes that can be changed,
but I always work with the
default one because I personally don't
care about the development environment, what
I value is the code.  Okay?  More
things.  What else can I change?
Well, if for example we are going to see it
here, we are going to create a new file.  I don't
want to open
there.  Open editors, no, but I want open
folder.
Look, file, open, file itself.  Okay, I'm
going to desktop, I'm going to the first
test and eh opening open.
Okay, another thing I can do is
increase the
text size,
increase
the text size.  Or I press
control plus the plus key and control plus
the minus key to zoom in on
the entire interface
or to
zoom out on the entire interface.
Okay, another thing I can do in
preferences
in settings,
let's see, is in text editor change
the font color, okay?  So,
font size, for example 24
here, okay, I go out and as you can see now the
code is bigger, okay?  Or code to
the beast, you know?  Front, code 48. I
'm doing it really hard so you can
see it.
Well, I can change,
not only can I change
the size of the entire interface,
but I can also change the font and
font size of the
specific editor.
What does it give us?  Hey,
what does Visual Studio give us?  Well,
what Visual Studio gives us, as you can see,
are tools, I insist, theoretically
to make working more comfortable.  Okay, me
too, pay attention,
right?  Oh, come on, go on.  I don't recommend it,
eh, how would I put it?  Don't get too deep
into Visual Studio
or you might get lost.
and you can distract yourself
from what's important.
And the important thing is to learn the code.
A development environment should be
easy to learn code in.  The
moment a
development environment becomes a
distraction, that's when we start to run into
problems.  Okay?
Good.  And now next, And now
next what I'm going to do is,
well, on the one hand, edit
programs.
So everything we're doing
up to this point, we can
do it within Visual Studio.  This
means that I can come here
and I can go to development environments and I
can go to installation and I can go to
program editing and I can go to
exercises, right?  And I can here.  Hello
hello.  Click, click.  A moment that has
been fried.  I'm going to drink in the
meantime.
Well, it's fried, but
fried, fried, fried, fried.
Now, now.  But don't believe it yourself either.
Let's see.